Tony Teixeira

805.689.0808 | hello@tonyit.com | linkedin.com/in/tonyteixeira

PROFILE

Marketing and sales operations professional with eight years of experience in small business, startup, and enterprise environments. A proponent of continuous learning with a passion for business and technology. Entrepreneurial minded and enjoy working for companies that I believe in and support.

KEY SKILLS

Salesforce • Process optimization • Analysis • Reporting • Sales enablement • Marketo • Pardot • WordPress • Google Analytics • HTML • CSS • JavaScript • jQuery • Swift • Apex • Visualforce • RESTful APIs • Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop

EXPERIENCE

HG Insights — Santa Barbara, CA / Remote

Sales Operations Manager

September 2017-Present

- Salesforce administrator responsible for day-to-day operations and overall system integrity.
- Refactored and built upon triggers, classes, and automation tools within Salesforce to improve and streamline business processes.
- Developed an Apex integration for lead, contact, and account enrichment using 3rd party APIs.
- Built data visualization within an AppExchange product using Lightning Design System and jQuery.
- Led the migration and implementation of the marketing automation system from Pardot to Marketo.
- On-boarded a new global sales team during an acquisition without hindering sales performance.
- Architected the merge of two company websites into a single entity during a company rebrand.

QAD Inc. — Santa Barbara, CA

Marketing Systems Specialist

May 2016 - Aug 2017

- Actively developed dynamically branded landing page and email templates for Marketo.
- Rewrote internal iOS applications used at company events for registration and expo booth scanners.
- Pursued cross-team projects to find solutions to improve internal tools used throughout the company.
- Built reports and dashboard to expose KPIs to sales and marketing teams.

Marketing Operations Specialist

Aug 2015 - Apr 2016

- Supported international marketing teams to ensure brand consistency and adherence to best practices.
- Designed and managed scalable nurture, webinar, and event programs/campaigns.
- Optimized email campaigns through a data-driven approach of continuous improvement.

EDUCATION

California State University, Stanislaus

Master of Business Administration (MBA) - Distinction, Beta Gamma Sigma Honor Society Bachelor of Science, Business Administration - Marketing concentration

AWARDS

QAD — Global Marketing Impact - Innovation